Liang Jia (Lj) Jiang 9722 57th Ave Queens, New York, 11368 (716) 263-8575 LjTechStack@gmail.com https://github.com/LjTechStack

SUMMARY

Experienced Application Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Java, Python, Computer Science, and Spring Framework. Strong business development professional with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) focused in Computer Science from SUNY at Buffalo.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

Proficient: Java8, Java7

• Familiar: JS, Python, Scala, SQL (Orcale, H2)

Software

- Software Packages: IntelliJ, Git (Github, BitBucket), Eclipse, Kubernetes, Docker, ELK stack
- Frameworks: SpringBatch, Spring MVC, AEM, Gatling

EXPERIENCE

Application Developer

November 2018– Present

Williams Sonoma

- Developed with Java, an expanded feature that allow user to run task in parallel, increasing user ability to work more efficient.
- Worked on an implementing batching to existing CMS build on AEM to improve function by 30% and eliminated server crashing on AEM.
- Implemented new micro-service application to migrate workload from existing CMS application using Java with Spring Framework along with Docker, Kubernetes, ELK.
- Built relationship with external team around the global, working closely with teams in California and India, through Zoom, Slack, and Outlook.
- Developed additional frontend feature that is display on westelm.com using Backbone JS.
- Maintained code quality through manual testing of feature and unit test using Jest.
- Upheld agile practices with monthly releases and actively engaging in user feedback.

Application Developer

September 2018 – November 2018

Bank of America

- Maintained data quality within an internal search engine, by testing result set from multiple SoR (Systems of Record).
- Developed a Python script to log failing result test from nightly jobs and perform auto runs on failed test cases to insure data is really faulty, saving time during business hour when comparing result set.

Application Developer Analyst

November 2016 – April 2018

Fannie Mae

- Worked on a service platform project to accelerate mortgage settlements between buyer and seller, a task that has been done offline previously, with around 20 clients the first year we broker over 40 Million USD within the application in Java using Spring Framework.
- Built a relationship system within the application to allow client to establish their own relationship
 and special pricing with other clients without the need of an internal user to create the
 relationship.
- Developed application following test principles such as BDD (Behavior Driven Development using Java and testing with Selenium and Cucumber.
- Upheld agile practices with monthly releases and actively engaging in user feedback.

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo

December 2015

Buffalo, NY

• Bachelors of Science in Computer Science